Guide to the Amy Biehl Collection
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Amy Biehl collection
1989-1996
SC0830
Jackson, Kennell A., 1941-2005.
0.75 Linear feet
Collection includes a copy of her honors thesis "Chester Crocker and the Negotiations for Namibian Independence: The Role of the Individual in Recent American Foreign Policy," 1989, and her paper "Observations on Namibian Independence," 1989, with a cover letter to Jackson from Biehl; clippings and press releases on her death; materials from her memorial service at Stanford, including text of remarks by Steve Stedman and Rich Schavone; letters to Jackson and one outgoing response, 1993-97; transcript of the Truth and Reconciliation Commission Amnesty Hearings for the men convicted of her death, 1997; and newsletters, by-laws, and other materials of the Amy Biehl Foundation, 1995-96.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Amy Elizabeth Biehl earned her A.B. at Stanford University in 1989; Kennell Jackson was her professor and advisor on her senior honors thesis. After graduation she worked with the National Democratic Institute for International Affairs, working in Namibia, South Africa, Burundi, Cote d'Ivoire, Congo, Guyana, Suriname and Zambia. She was in South Africa as a Fulbright Scholar when she was killed in August 1993.
Description of the Collection
Collection includes a copy of her honors thesis "Chester Crocker and the Negotiations for Namibian Independence: The Role of the Individual in Recent American Foreign Policy," 1989, and her paper "Observations on Namibian Independence," 1989, with a cover letter to Jackson from Biehl; clippings and press releases on her death; materials from her memorial service at Stanford, including text of remarks by Steve Stedman and Rich Schavone; letters to Jackson and one outgoing response, 1993-97; transcript of the Truth and Reconciliation Commission Amnesty Hearings for the men convicted of her death, 1997; and newsletters, by-laws, and other materials of the Amy Biehl Foundation, 1995-96.
Access Terms
Amy Biehl Foundation.; Biehl, Amy.; Jackson, Kennell A., 1941-2005.; Schavone, Richard Michael.; South Africa. Truth and Reconciliation Commission.; Stedman, Steven John.
Collection Contents
- Materials
  - Amy Biehl's Honors Thesis, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Article and Ph.D. Statement of Purpose by Biehl, circa 1989 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Photo of Biehl, ? (~1989) (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Amy Biehl Foundation, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Clippings, Press Releases, 1993-1994 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Grilger, T. Frank, Simmons College Convocation Speech, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Letters to Kennel Jackson with Outgoing Letter, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - South African Newsletter (Stanford University Computer List), 1993 Sep 10 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Stanford Memorial Service, 1993 Sep 3 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Memorial Service Notice, 1993 Oct 10 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Amy Biehl Foundation Newsletter, 1996? (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Amy Biehl Foundation, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Articles, 1994, 1996-1997 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Biehl, "Observation on Namibian Independence" w/ note to KJ, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence from Peter Biehl, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Reflections, Vol. 2, No. 4, with cover letter, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - TRC Amnesty Hearing - Death of Amy Biehl, transcript, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 7)